mfg.com 2016-10-20

# Privacy and Security Policy | MFG.com

##  Privacy Policy

Welcome to the MFG.com, Inc. and subsidiaries Websites including MFG.com, SourcingParts.com, MFGx.com, MFGTextiles.com and MFGQuote.com, collectively the "MFG.com" Websites. MFG.com provides access to its Websites to the public and members subject to the following Privacy Policy to reflect our firm commitment to you, our valued Members and Users. You are encouraged to read this Privacy Policy to ensure you understand MFG.com's practices **.**

Where MFG.com has provided you with a translation of the English language version of the Privacy Policy, then you agree that the translation is provided for your convenience only and that the English language versions of the Privacy Policy will govern your relationship with MFG.com. If there is any contradiction between what the English language version of the Privacy Policy says and what a translation says, then the English language version shall take precedence.

**Collection of Your Personal Information**

MFG.com collects personal and company information on our Websites. Personal information is any information that can be used to identify an individual or company, and may include, but is not limited to, IP address, company name, individuals name, email address, postal or other physical address, title, telephone number, cell phone number, fax number, occupation, and other information required to provide a service, deliver a product, or carry out a transaction you have requested.

**Uses of Your Personal Information**

 Some of the ways we may use your personal information include:

  * To contact you regarding our products and services by all contact information you have specified in your profile such as regular mail, email, phone and fax
  * To provide customer feedback and support
  *  Marketing or promotional activities. Personal information may be collected to administer those programs
  * To conduct questionnaires and surveys in order to provide new and better products. Your participation in any questionnaires or survey is voluntary
  * To understand more about you, so we can personalize newsletters and Websites to your preferences
  * To meet contract obligations.

**Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information**

We need your help in keeping the personal information you have shared with us accurate and up to date. Please notify us of any changes to your personal information or directly enter the updated information to your personal profile online.

**Non-personal Information Collection**

In some instances, MFG.com may collect non-personal (aggregate or demographic) data through cookies, web logs, and web beacons. This information is used to better understand and improve the usability, performance and effectiveness of the MFG.com Websites.

**Sharing Your Personal Information**

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third-parties for marketing purposes unless you have granted us permission to do so. We may share your personal information within MFG.com or any of our worldwide subsidiaries for purposes of data processing or storage. We may also share your personal information with authorized third-party agents or contractors in order to provide a requested service or transaction. We only provide third-party agents with the minimum amount of personal information necessary to complete the requested service or transaction.

We may respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process by disclosing your personal information and other related information, if necessary. We also may choose to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

We may collect and possibly share personal information and any other additional information available to us in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of MFG.com's Terms of Use, Security Policies or as otherwise required by law.

While navigating MFG.com's Websites you may be directed to content or functionality that is hosted by a third party supplier, not on MFG.com. This is typically done to host special events, such as contests or for MFG.com Partner sites. When information is collected on behalf of MFG.com exclusively, MFG.com's Privacy Policy will be referenced on the site and will govern how your information is used. For other, non-MFG.com sites, the site owner's privacy policy should be referenced. We will ask you for your opt-in consent to share your personal information with a third party for any other reason.

**Personalization**

We may customize our Websites or newsletters for certain users based on the information they previously provided or that was collected through MFG.com in order to enhance the overall web experience.

**Security of Your Personal Information**

MFG.com is committed to protecting the personal information you share with us. We utilize a combination of security technologies, procedures, and organizational measures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When we transfer sensitive personal data (for example, credit card information) over the Internet, we protect it using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology. While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit. We recommend you to take every precaution in protecting your personal information when you are on the Internet. For example, change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers when creating passwords, and make sure you use a secure browser.

**Cookies**

MFG.com utilizes cookies, although you can still access most elements of MFG.com Websites even if you choose to disable cookies in your browser. Some of our Websites will not allow you to complete certain activities if cookies are disabled.

We use multiple third parties to monitor web traffic, statistics, advertisement 'click-through', and other activities on MFG.com. Where authorized by MFG.com, such third parties may use cookies, MFG.com's web log files, web beacons, and other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous aggregate statistics on MFG.com's visitors. We also include web beacons in HTML-formatted e-mail newsletters in order to count how many newsletters (or particular articles, links, etc.) are being accessed.

**Data Retention**

MFG.com will not retain your personal information longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations.

**Newsgroups/Blogs/Wikis/Forums**

MFG.com Newsgroups, Blogs, Wikis and Forums are public. Please consider this before posting material to them. MFG.com moderators of these Newsgroups, Blogs, Wiki's and Forums reserve the right to remove offensive or off-topic material including material that is considered by moderators to not be in the best interest of community standards.

**Site Links**

Our Websites contain links to other Websites. However, MFG.com is not responsible for the privacy content or conduct of any such Websites.

**Logging Your IP Address**

We log your IP address to help us locate any problems with our server as well as assisting us in the administration of the site.

**Supplementary Information**

Should your demographic information prove to be incomplete we may use outside third parties to supplement your record.

**Removal from Database**

Our users have the choice of not receiving communications from us. Users can also remove their information from our database in order not to receive future communications or to no longer benefit from our service. To be removed, contact us at [support@mfg.com](mailto:support@mfg.com) and title your e-mail REMOVE FROM DATABASE.

**Corrections / Updates**

Many of the MFG.com Websites will allow users on-line access to change and modify information previously provided. Also, certain users of the MFG.com Websites may contact us at [support@mfg.com](mailto:support@mfg.com) to have us make the changes for you.

##  Security Policy

Welcome to the MFG.com, Inc. and subsidiaries Websites including MFG.com, SourcingParts.com, MFGx.com, MFGTextiles.com and MFGQuote.com, collectively the "MFG.com" Websites. MFG.com provides access to its Websites to the public and members and has put in place the Security Policies noted below. By accessing, viewing, posting, using or downloading materials from these Websites, you agree to be bound by these Security Policies. If you do not agree with these Security Policies do not use these Websites.

Where MFG.com has provided you with a translation of the English language version of the Security Policy, then you agree that the translation is provided for your convenience only and that the English language versions of the Security Policy will govern your relationship with MFG.com. If there is any contradiction between what the English language version of the Security Policy says and what a translation says, then the English language version shall take precedence.

**Security Measures**

We know that security is crucial to you and we consider security to be a top priority. We devote significant resources to continually optimize our security infrastructure and this includes continuous monitoring and improvement.

**Among other security measures, MFG.com provides:**

  * Experienced, professional engineers and security specialists dedicated to round-the-clock data and systems protection.
  * Continuous deployment of proven, up-to-date security technologies, including proprietary products developed for MFG.com.
  * Ongoing evaluation of emerging security developments and threats.
  * Complete redundancy throughout the entire MFG.com online infrastructure.
  * Client Auditing (Notably in the sectors of Aero-Defense).

**Physical Security**

Our production equipment is collocated in Geneva, Switzerland and Atlanta, USA at facilities that provide 24-hour physical security, redundant electrical generators, redundant data center air conditioners, and other backup equipment designed to keep servers continually up and running.

**Perimeter Defense**

The network perimeter is protected by multiple firewalls and monitored by intrusion detection systems Ñ all sourced from industry-leading security vendors. In addition, MFG.com monitors and analyzes firewall logs to proactively identify security threats.

**Data Encryption**

MFG.com leverages the strongest encryption products to protect customer data and communications, including 128-bit SSL Certification and 1024-bit RSA public keys. The lock icon in the browser indicates that data is fully shielded from access while in transit.

**User Authentication**

Users access MFG.com only with a valid username and password combination, which is encrypted via SSL while in transmission. An encrypted session ID cookie is used to uniquely identify each user. For added security, the session key is automatically scrambled and re-established in the background at regular intervals. MFG.com website username and passwords are to be kept confidential. You may not disclose or share your username or password with any third parties.

**Application Security**

Our robust application security model prevents one MFG.com customer from accessing another's data. This security model is reapplied with every request and enforced for the entire duration of a user session.

**Internal Systems Security**

Inside of the perimeter firewalls, the systems are safeguarded by network address translation, port redirection and more. The specific details of these features are proprietary.

**Operating System Security**

MFG.com enforces tight operating system-level security by using a minimal number of access points to all production servers. We protect all operating system accounts with strong passwords, and production servers do not share a master password.

**Database Security**

Whenever possible, database access is controlled at the operating system and database connection level for additional security. Access to production databases is restricted to a limited number of points, and production databases do not share a master password database.

**Third Party Caching Service**

MFG.com Websites utilize a "best of breed" third party caching service to ensure faster load and response times of MFG.com web pages as well as accelerated route optimization to ensure data is served up to users in the most efficient manner possible. No proprietary user data is stored on these third party servers in the form of cached data. The elimination of the number of hops in accessing data as well as the third party vendors stringent security methods provide additional security and integrity to the MFG.com Websites.

**Server Management Security**

All data entered into the MFG.com sourcing application by a customer is owned by that customer. MFG.com employees do not have direct access to the MFG.com production equipment, except where necessary for system management, maintenance, monitoring, and backups. MFG.com does not utilize any managed service providers. The MFG.com systems engineering team provides all system management, maintenance, monitoring, and backups.

**Reliability and Backup**

All networking components, SSL accelerators, load balancers, Web servers, and application servers are configured in a redundant configuration. All customer data is stored on a database served by a database server cluster for redundancy. All customer data is stored on carrier-class disk storage using RAID disks and multiple data paths. All customer data, up to the last committed transaction, is automatically backed up to a primary tape library on a nightly basis. Backup tapes are moved to secure, fire-resistant, off-site storage on a regular basis.

**Security**

Our site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under the control of MFG.com. We use username and password protection for users. We have a password retrieval process for users who prove they are authorized to obtain their password, via their valid email account. Transactions involving financial data are only processed using secure server technology. All data is stored on Web and database servers that are secured from physical public access. Any use of a robot, bot, spider, or other automatic or manual device or process to monitor, copy, scrape, or otherwise unlawfully access any pages on the MFG.com websites will be prosecuted to the full extent under the law.

This Privacy & Security Policy was last Updated October 15, 2009.
